<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:rawvoice="http://www.rawvoice.com/rawvoiceRssModule/" xmlns:googleplay="http://www.google.com/schemas/play-podcasts/1.0" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Archived The Voluntary Life</title>
<atom:link href="http://orcahealth.canvascreative.co/voluntary.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<link>http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/</link>
<description/>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 1:07:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-US</language>
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.4.2</generator>
<!--
 podcast_generator="Blubrry PowerPress/6.3.1" mode="simple"
-->
<itunes:summary>
  Ideas for finding freedom in an unfree world. Interviews and discussions about entrepreneurship, investing, financial freedom, Getting Things Done (GTD), long term travel and freedom in personal relationships.
</itunes:summary>
<itunes:author>The Voluntary Life</itunes:author>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:image href="http://podcasts.thevoluntarylife.com/huge_white.jpg" />
<itunes:owner>
<itunes:name>The Voluntary Life</itunes:name>
<itunes:email>jake@thevoluntarylife.com</itunes:email>
</itunes:owner>
<managingEditor>noreply@blogger.com (Jake Desyllas)</managingEditor>
<itunes:subtitle/>
<image>
<title>The Voluntary Life</title>
<url>
http://psychologybookclub.org/thevoluntarylife/blogger_logo.png
</url>
<link>http://thevoluntarylife.com/</link>
</image>
<itunes:category text="Business"></itunes:category>

<item>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 1:07:45 +0000</pubDate>
<title>People Who Control America</title>
<link>http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/</guid>
<comments></comments>
<category>
<![CDATA[ Uncategorized ]]>
</category>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>Doc from youtube</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://orcahealth.canvascreative.co/youtube-doc.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
<title>89 Financial Consciousness: An Interview With Mike</title>
<link>http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/</link>
<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/</guid>
<comments></comments>
<category>
<![CDATA[ Uncategorized ]]>
</category>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Mike talks about how he saved his way to financial freedom, without a college degree or a high-powered job. He shares his thoughts on how to be conscious about your relationship with money and explains some of the methods for saving your way to wealth that work for him. As always, do your own research- we&#39;re not financial advisors and this&amp;nbsp;is just our opinions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E089_financial_consciousness.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E089_financial_consciousness.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
<itunes:duration>1:00:</itunes:duration>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-12-17T15:14:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>88 Why I Feared The Free Market</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Some thoughts on what it is that frightens people about the free market, based on my own experience of what frightened me. The fear of the market is often expressed in very abstract arguments about whether free markets would really work (if we had them) and what their relationship is to poverty etc. However, &amp;nbsp;at an individual level, I believe people fear markets because of how vulnerable you can feel when taking part in voluntary exchange:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trade on the free market involves selling to others. This opens you up to the potential for rejection and failure, which can be scary.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The division of labour involves choosing to specialise in some skill or area of work that might one day become obsolete, which can feel vulnerable. It also involves taking responsibility for specific outcomes- the buck stops with you- which challenges any defences against the fear of responsibility.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Respect for private property rights involves looking after your stuff and respecting other people&#39;s stuff. This opens you up to the potential for feelings of humiliation if you don&#39;t understand how or why others have made a success of selling when you have not yet been able to.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&#39;s understandable to fear the free market. It can be scary to launch yourself into entrepreneurship, as well as being wonderful. However, some people project their personal fears of the market into abstract theories: they blame the market itself for the world&#39;s ills. That approach will prevent you from overcoming your fears and limit your potential.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E088_fear_of_the_free_market.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E088_fear_of_the_free_market.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>



<item>
<pubDate>2012-12-13T03:05:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>87 An Expat Entrepreneur In Chile</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is an interview with Edwin, an expat entrepreneur in Chile. Edwin talks about his experience on an entrepreneurship visa in Chile and shares his thoughts about the pros and cons of Chile as a place to live and to create a startup in. He discusses other things to consider regarding coming to Chile as an entrepreneur, including his views on the Start-up Chile grant, some comparisons of cost of living and considerations on quality of life in Chile as an expat. You can contact Edwin at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:edwininchile@gmail.com&quot;&gt;edwininchile@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E087_expat_entrepreneur_in_chile.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E087_expat_entrepreneur_in_chile.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-12-03T12:16:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>86 Teaching Entrepreneurship to Kids: An Interview with Eduardo Marty</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;An interview with Eduardo Marty, who founded&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.junior.org.ar/&quot;&gt;Junior Achievement in Argentina&lt;/a&gt; and in many other Latin American countries. Junior Achievement is a charity that teaches entrepreneurship to children and young adults.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eduardo has also held academic posts as professor at the University Francisco Marroquín, Guatemala, and the University of Buenos Aires. He&amp;nbsp;is one of the few academics who is truly passionate about the need for young people to learn the practical skills of entrepreneurship. As he says in the interview; &quot;the problem with intellectuals is that they are always running out of money&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this entertaining interview, he discusses his experiences and his adventures in a life dedicated to helping kids realise their entrepreneurial potential, including a narrow escape from being imprisoned in Cuba when he tried to establish Junior Achievement there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E086_interview_eduardo_marty.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E086_interview_eduardo_marty.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-11-27T03:13:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>85 Freedom From Intellectual Heroes</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about gaining freedom from intellectual heroes. I share some thoughts about how to extract the best ideas from thinkers that you admire, without relying on someone else to think for you. I talk about some ways I have found for gaining intellectual independence, including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Taking apart the &quot;package deal&quot; of a set of new ideas to use the ones that work and discard the ones that don&#39;t.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Learning to trust your own judgement: if an idea doesn&#39;t make sense to you, it&#39;s probably because the idea is incoherent.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Starting from the assumption that &quot;everything is a remix&quot;, even if an idea appears to be very original or is presented as very new.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ultimately, I believe intellectual independence is about giving up the emotional search for leaders. It is a part of growing up and being an adult to stop looking for intellectual heroes and to treat every thinker as someone who puts their pants on one leg at a time, just like you and me. A really important aspect of intellectual freedom is to give up deference to our heroes- to take what we can from their ideas and own those ideas for ourselves, so that we truly think for ourselves. That&#39;s what free people do, they think for themselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E085_freedom_from_intellectual_heroes.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E085_freedom_from_intellectual_heroes.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-11-20T01:07:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>84 Interview With Joel Bowman</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QzblD2JCYjs/UKrRs1anaYI/AAAAAAAAAgg/wKxxAnFX5d8/s1600/JoelBowman.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-QzblD2JCYjs/UKrRs1anaYI/AAAAAAAAAgg/wKxxAnFX5d8/s200/JoelBowman.jpg&quot; width=&quot;135&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is an interview with Joel Bowman, the managing editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dailyreckoning.com/&quot;&gt;The Daily Reckoning&lt;/a&gt; e-newsletter email and former managing editor of the Rude Awakening. After completing his degree in media communications and journalism in his home country of Australia, Joel moved to Baltimore to join the Agora Financial team. His keen interest in travel and macroeconomics first took him to New York where he regularly reported from Wall Street, and he now writes from and lives all over the world.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joel currently lives in Buenos Aires. In the interview he gives his perspective on life as an expat in the city and provides an overview of what has been happening to the economy in Argentina recently.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Apologies for the technical problems with the recording: the audio cuts out very briefly intermittently throughout the interview, but it is still possible to understand the interview.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E084_interview_joel_bowman.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E084_interview_joel_bowman.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-11-11T12:48:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>83 Introduction to Investing</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode covers a lot of questions I faced getting started in investing as a private investor and my own experience in tackling these questions:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why invest (i.e. why not just leave your money in a bank)?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Who is going to manage your investments, an external manager or yourself?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are you going to be an active investor (e.g. analysing individual securities for value and trading more often) or a passive investor (e.g. using index funds and trading less often)?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Which asset classes are you going to invest in (e.g. stocks, bonds, precious metals, cash)? How will you allocate and balance assets in your portfolio?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Which individual securities are you going to select within each asset class (e.g if you decide to buy bonds, which individual bonds will you choose)?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When should you start investing, within the context of your overall personal financial planning?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When should you buy or sell individual assets? Will you try to time the market or will you automatically rebalance a portfolio based on an asset&amp;nbsp;allocation&amp;nbsp;strategy?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Where should you invest? Should you have geographic diversification and if so, what kind?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;You can also get more information about the concept of the permanent portfolio discussed in this episode in&amp;nbsp;Harry Browne&#39;s book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031226321X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=031226321X&quot;&gt;Fail-Safe Investing&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and in many of the previous Voluntary Life podcast episodes on&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/search/label/investment&quot;&gt; investing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As always regarding investment, do your own research. I am not an advisor and this isn&#39;t advice of any kind, it&#39;s just my own opinions based on my experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E083_introduction_to_investing.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E083_introduction_to_investing.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-10-30T00:17:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>82 Savings Vs Wage Slavery</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This&amp;nbsp;episode&amp;nbsp;is about saving money and it&#39;s relationship with freedom. Many people are trapped in a &quot;wage slavery&quot; lifestyle, living from month to month. Although their income rises during their career, their expenses scale correspondingly (or even lead ahead, creating debt). There are two approaches to developing the savings that allow get you out of this trap:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;One route is to increase earnings without increasing expenses, creating savings. The difficulty with this approach is that&amp;nbsp;the higher the income, the bigger the tendency or temptation to spend more on a more comfortable lifestyle.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The other approach is to decrease expenses without decreasing earnings, by focussing on minimising living expenses as much as possible. The challenge with this approach is to do so without losing income (for example, moving to a low cost location might not make it possible to keep a well paid job).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jake talks about his experience focussing on the first approach and discusses some of the benefits in terms of freedom that saving provides:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Developing an emergency fund of approximately&amp;nbsp;3 months expenses reduces a huge amount of stress associated with living month to month and enables you to cope with unexpected expenses or irregular cashflow.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Developing savings to cover 1 year of expenses opens up a huge degree of freedom, for example to start your own business, to leave a job if you don&#39;t like it or even to change your life in other ways such as by emigrating to another country.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;This podcast and blog summary contains only personal opinions, it does not constitute financial advice and I am not a financial advisor.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E082_savings_vs_wage_slavery.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E082_savings_vs_wage_slavery.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-10-22T19:45:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>81 Freedom From Debt</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about the freedom that comes from getting out of debt.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We live in a time when being in debt is the norm in our society.&amp;nbsp;The basis of the debt culture lies in government policies (such as inflating the money supply and artificially lowering interest rates) that actively incentivise individuals to get into debt.&amp;nbsp;These government policies filter through into opportunities for debt everywhere that are encouraged by mainstream culture. For example: student loans for college, credit for&amp;nbsp;consumer goods,&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;the mainstream&amp;nbsp;ideal of home ownership and the&amp;nbsp;mortgage debt that goes with it.&amp;nbsp;Debt becomes a way of life for most people, which can lead to rationalising it and being over-optimistic about it&#39;s impact.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ultimately debt always reduces your financial freedom. It is always restricting the freedom of action of &amp;nbsp;your future self.&amp;nbsp;Jake talks about his experience of being in debt and getting out of debt. The podcast goes on to focus on the benefits of being debt free:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The main benefit is in increasing your freedom of action when you are out of debt&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When debt is cleared it removes a constant source of worry&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Deciding on how to use your money can be a pleasure again and an aspect of freedom&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Removing debt is an aspect of self-care: it is financial self-care&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;This podcast and blog summary contains only my personal opinions, it does not constitute financial advice and I am not a financial advisor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E081_freedom_from_debt.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E081_freedom_from_debt.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-10-15T15:58:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>80 Financial Freedom Milestones</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This episode is a about the significant milestones along the way towards achieving financial freedom. In my opinion, reaching each of these milestones brings you closer to being financially free and it is useful to take a step back and consider what the steps along the way of your journey will be. Some milestones to consider are suggested:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Financial independence&lt;/b&gt; or&amp;nbsp;&quot;paying your own way&quot;, whereby you are sustaining yourself from your job or work income on a month to month basis. You are not living off parents, not living from significant subsidies from your family, not accumulating student debt and not accumulating credit card debt. It&#39;s important to note role how going to college significantly delays reaching this milestone and how many people do not achieve this milestone until they are in their 30s or later.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Achieving positive net worth&lt;/b&gt;, whereby your assets are greater than your liabilities. This is often what people mean when they talk about &quot;getting out of debt&quot; (although that is not exactly the same). It is important to be aware that consumer credit and mortgate debt can significantly hinder or delay you reaching this goal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Making your first investment,&lt;/b&gt; for example by purchasing an income producing asset like shares or bonds. &amp;nbsp;The key distinction is that this is not just money you haven&#39;t used yet which you are putting aside until &amp;nbsp;you spend it, it is money you do not intend to ever spend. You are putting this money to work for you creating income. Although a lot of people consider purchasing a house with a mortgage as their first big investment, a property for your own use is really a consumption item.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Net worth surpasses annual expenses-&lt;/b&gt; in other words, your&amp;nbsp;savings (assets) could keep you going for 1 year if you needed to. This means you have a significant safety buffer, but if you did have to use your savings&amp;nbsp;it would mean that you consume your capital and you would be back to square 1.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Annual passive investment income becomes larger than your annual expenses: &lt;/b&gt;this is real financial freedom, as &amp;nbsp;you can now&amp;nbsp;live off your passive income. For this to be sustainable it needs to take into account the effect of inflation, taxes etc. However, once you can sustainably live from your passive income, you are financially free.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This podcast and blog summary contains only my personal opinions, it does not constitute financial advice and I am not a financial advisor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E080_financial_freedom_milestones.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E080_financial_freedom_milestones.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-10-08T18:45:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>79 Entrepreneurship Part 11: Free Your Ass And Your Mind Will Follow</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about the entrepreneurial mindset. What kind of thinking do you need to be an entrepreneur? More importantly, how will doing entrepreneurship change the way that you think? Jake talks about some key aspects of the entrepreneurial mentality including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;cultivating optimism and&amp;nbsp;perseverance&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;using the trial and error method&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;acceptance of failure and the possibility of failure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a deep rooted focus on sales&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a results-oriented outlook&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;thrift and developing a reluctance to spend time or money without demonstrated good value&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;being market oriented and having a tendency to look for voluntary solutions in all of life&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E079_free_your_ass_your_mind_will_follow.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E079_free_your_ass_your_mind_will_follow.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-10-01T23:45:00.002+01:00</pubDate>
<title>78 Entrepreneurship Part 10: Going Into Business With Others</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about the issue of shared ownership in business. It covers key questions that anyone considering going into business with others will face, including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Should you go into business with others or be a sole owner-entrepreneur?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you do go into business with others, how will you split ownership?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How will you ensure that the owners are all incentivised to add value to the business? In other words, how will you avoid the free-rider problem?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How are you going to make decisions together efficiently and avoid deadlock?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What will you do if the owners no longer want to work together, or one of them wants out?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jake provides his own experience in facing these questions and summarises some of the options available to consider. It&#39;s up to you to decide what the best choices are for your own business. This podcast will help you make these decisions.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E078_going_into_business_with_others.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E078_going_into_business_with_others.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-09-24T15:14:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>77 Internationalising Yourself</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mtedo5O34RU/UGBqN1dRfUI/AAAAAAAAAfo/wmfGS1qa1CY/s1600/earth.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-mtedo5O34RU/UGBqN1dRfUI/AAAAAAAAAfo/wmfGS1qa1CY/s200/earth.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode discusses ways in which you can overcome the limitations of the country in which you happen to have been born and, as much as possible, live with the whole of planet earth as your homeland. The topics covered include:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Travelling and seeing the world, to help you make conscious choices about where you want to spend your life&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Taking the opportunity to live abroad for extended periods of time so that you can experience life in different parts of the world&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Learning another language and giving yourself different tools to think with&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Internationalising some of your assets, as geo-political diversification in case of catastrophic events such as a war.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you have the opportunity, taking advantage of the chance to obtain dual nationality to further extend your flexibility in terms of where you can work or live.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E077_internationalising_yourself.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-09-17T22:22:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>76 The Permanent Portfolio: Author Interview With Craig Rowland</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rT211u7YRxw/UFePAxyITbI/AAAAAAAAAfU/WPvnKMk7_JA/s1600/ppbook.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-rT211u7YRxw/UFePAxyITbI/AAAAAAAAAfU/WPvnKMk7_JA/s200/ppbook.jpg&quot; width=&quot;131&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is an interview with Craig Rowland, who is the&amp;nbsp;co-author of a new book called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1118288254/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1118288254&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&quot;&gt;The Permanent Portfolio: Harry Browne&#39;s Long-Term Investment Strategy&lt;/a&gt;. Craig is also&amp;nbsp;author of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://crawlingroad.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Crawling Road&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;blog and host of&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gyroscopicinvesting.com/forum&quot;&gt;permanent portfolio forum&lt;/a&gt;. In the episode we discuss the Permanent Portfolio strategy and many of the insights from Craig&#39;s new book. We talk about the way in which the Permanent Portfolio approach differs from other investment strategies including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The choice of being an independent investor as opposed to entrusting your money to someone else&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Achieving diversification in investing, as opposed to the&amp;nbsp;Warren Buffet&amp;nbsp;quote&amp;nbsp;of &quot;putting all your eggs in one basket and watching the basket very closely&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Using an asset allocation strategy based on identifying how assets react to each of the possible economic conditions, as opposed to asset allocation based on correlation studies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The problems with trying to time the market in investing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The benefits of a passive investing approach that rebalances according to a strategy of maintaining diversification.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;We also talk about some particular practical issues relating to the portfolio including&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Creating your own portfolio versus using the Permanent Portfolio fund (and differences in the fund&#39;s approach to the classic PP strategy)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The growth of passive indexing strategies in stocks and how this aspect of the Permanent Portfolio approach is now more mainstream&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Craig&#39;s thoughts on how best to own gold bullion and the tradeoff between convenience and safety.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How the permanent portfolio can help independent investors in the&amp;nbsp;current&amp;nbsp;context of artificially low interest rates and Quantitative Easing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;You can also get more information about the concept of the permanent portfolio&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;Harry Browne&#39;s book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031226321X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=031226321X&quot;&gt;Fail-Safe Investing&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and in many of the previous Voluntary Life podcast episodes on&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/search/label/investment&quot;&gt; investing&lt;/a&gt;. Neither Craig nor Jake are financial advisors or dealers of any kind and this podcast only expresses our opinions.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E076_the_permanent_portfolio_interview.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E076_the_permanent_portfolio_interview.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-09-11T00:20:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>75 The Most Advanced Democracy On Earth (Probably Not What You Think)</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about the most advanced democracy on earth. It is about the most effective system we have for letting everyone have their say, working together to change society in a non-violent way.... Oh and it&#39;s probably not what you think.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Show Notes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mises.org/document/1164/The-AntiCapitalistic-Mentality&quot;&gt;Ludwig Von Mises&#39; &quot;The Anti-capitalistic Mentality&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;br /&gt;Churchill&#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.quotationspage.com/quote/364.html&quot;&gt;quote on democracy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Popper&quot;&gt;Karl Popper&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s views on&amp;nbsp;democracy can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0691019681/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0691019681&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&quot;&gt;The Open Society and Its Enemies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E075_the_most_advanced_democracy_on_earth.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E075_the_most_advanced_democracy_on_earth.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-09-04T09:23:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>74 City Air Makes You Free</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about where you choose to live and the impact that this choice can have on your level of freedom. Many people who have written about personal and political liberty have suggested a link between where you choose to live and how free you are. In the podcast we explore 3 different ideas about this choice:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The ideas in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/%3Ca%20href=%22http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1477469613/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1477469613&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20%22%3EWalden%3C/a%3E&quot;&gt;Walden&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by Henry David Thoreau: finding freedom by living self-sufficiently alone in a rural setting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The idea of &#39;Galts Gulch&#39; in &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/%3Ca%20href=%22http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0452011876/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0452011876&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20%22%3EAtlas%20Shrugged%3C/a%3E&quot;&gt;Atlas Shrugged&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by Ayn Rand: finding freedom by living in a small community of like-minded people (again in a rural setting with an emphasis on self-sufficiency)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The idea that &#39;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stadtluft_macht_frei&quot;&gt;City Air Makes You Free&lt;/a&gt;&#39;&lt;/i&gt; (expressed by writers such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0679644334/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0679644334&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&quot;&gt;Jane Jacobs&lt;/a&gt;): finding freedom in the division of labour and diversity that cities provide.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Arguably, the benefits of self-sufficiency have been overestimated in books like &lt;i&gt;Walden&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Atlas Shrugged&lt;/i&gt;, whereas the benefits of interdependence in cities have been under-appreciated by previous writers on liberty. It is suggested that Galt&#39;s Gulch wouldn&#39;t actually work in real life because it would lack the division of labour of a big city that is necessary to support the kind of advanced and specialised roles of it&#39;s inhabitants.&amp;nbsp;In contrast, living in a city can provide many opportunities for greater work and personal freedom because of the benefits of the division of labour in cities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;b&gt;Show Notes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Origin of the phrase &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stadtluft_macht_frei&quot;&gt;City Air Makes You Free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0679644334/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0679644334&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&quot;&gt;The Death and Life of Great American Cities&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;Jane Jacobs&lt;br /&gt;Previous episode of The Voluntary Life about &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2010/09/wilderness-as-freedom-walden-by-henry.html&quot;&gt;Walden by Henry David Thoreau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Previous episode of The Voluntary Life about&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2010/10/atlas-shrugged-by-ayn-rand.html&quot;&gt;Atlas Shrugged by Ayn Rand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E074_city_air_makes_you_free.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E074_city_air_makes_you_free.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-08-28T11:12:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>73 A Review of The Four Hour Work Week by Tim Ferriss</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6_qnu2DnV3M/UDyN-gW5MSI/AAAAAAAAAeg/hX0YP8YPa80/s1600/4hrww.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6_qnu2DnV3M/UDyN-gW5MSI/AAAAAAAAAeg/hX0YP8YPa80/s200/4hrww.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is a review of the book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307465357/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0307465357&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&quot;&gt;The 4-Hour Workweek: Escape 9-5, Live Anywhere, and Join the New Rich&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by Tim Ferriss. It is a skype conversation with a group of friends. The ideas that we discuss include:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;taking mini-retirements and getting out of a one-track career mentality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;extended travelling&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;testing new entrepreneurial ideas with sales pages on the web before starting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;outsourcing tasks to a virtual assistant&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tim Ferriss&#39; personality and how it influences the style and content of the book&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E073_the_4_hour_work_week.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E073_the_4_hour_work_week.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-08-21T00:10:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>72 How You Can Help End Poverty</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about how you as an individual can help alleviate poverty in a non-political, principled way. It&#39;s an economic view of how you can reduce poverty through economic development and the wealth that it generates. Jake presents ideas of the economist Ludwig Von Mises about how you can create economic progress and development, focussing on three key activities:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;creating technical innovation, which helps to make everything cheaper for everyone within the economy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;being an entrepreneur, which creates new value and wealth in the economy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;being a saver and investor, which provides resources for the future economic development (either of your own business or that of others)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The podcast discusses how each of these activities help reduce your own poverty and that of the world as a whole.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Show Notes&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mises.org/document/1164/The-AntiCapitalistic-Mentality&quot;&gt;Ludwig Von Mises The Anti-capitalistic Mentality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mises.org/document/3582/Against-Intellectual-Property&quot;&gt;Stephan Kinsella Against Intellectual Property&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E072_how_you_can_help_end_poverty.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E072_how_you_can_help_end_poverty.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-08-15T23:17:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>71 Computer Security and Privacy For Everyone</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is an interview with Kristov, an application security specialist, about what kind of measures individuals can take to ensure a level of security and privacy for their computers and their online life. In the interview, we cover security and privacy for a range of topics including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;email use&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;web browsing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;malware and viruses&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;password managers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;data storage&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;use of torrents&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;VOIP  and chat&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;application security for entrepreneurs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E071_computer_privacy_and_security.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E071_computer_privacy_and_security.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-08-07T19:22:00.001+01:00</pubDate>
<title>70 Becoming Who You Are Interview Part 2</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yHI_pZok_Xg/UA6bWbqhlHI/AAAAAAAAAd4/qkXpZiEjpqM/s1600/BWYAsquare.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yHI_pZok_Xg/UA6bWbqhlHI/AAAAAAAAAd4/qkXpZiEjpqM/s200/BWYAsquare.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;169&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;The second part of the interview from the B&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.becomingwhoyouare.net/2012/08/episode-010-interview-with-jake-from-the-voluntary-life-part-2/&quot;&gt;ecoming Who You Are Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. We talk about a whole range of topics including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The fear of criticism that can come up when putting creative work out there&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The challenges of being yourself at work&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The future of The Voluntary Life podcast&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The difference between abstract business planning and being conscious of what&#39;s really happening in your business now&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The balance between having dreams and staying in touch with reality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting support from the people in your life&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Doing what you love&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E070_BWYA_interview_part_2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E070_BWYA_interview_part_2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-08-01T15:30:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>69 Inflation: The Hidden Tax</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2Ma-lmNLOk0/UBk4Cplmg3I/AAAAAAAAAeI/xnPiXdqBFiI/s1600/inflationpickpocket.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;177&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-2Ma-lmNLOk0/UBk4Cplmg3I/AAAAAAAAAeI/xnPiXdqBFiI/s200/inflationpickpocket.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marcdemesel.be/&quot;&gt;Marc de Mesel&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;who was previously on the show talking &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2012/02/investing-in-europe-interview-with-marc.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;about investing in Europe&lt;/a&gt;. Marc runs a blog on&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marcdemesel.be/&quot;&gt; investing in Europe in dutch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://europeanpermanentportfolio.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;also an investing blog&amp;nbsp;in english&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this episode, Marc talks about the hidden tax that is inflation. We discuss the difference between official inflation figures and the real loss of purchasing power that ordinary people experience. We also talk about ways in which an individual investor or saver can cope with inflation, including the advantages and limitations of precious metals as an inflation hedge. The discussion is opinion only&amp;nbsp;and should not be considered any kind of financial advice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For more information about the concept of the permanent portfolio mentioned in the discussion, see Harry Browne&#39;s book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031226321X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=031226321X&quot;&gt;Fail-Safe Investing&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. You can also hear more about the Permanent Portfolio concept in &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.com/2010/05/investing-for-financial-freedom-two.html&quot;&gt;this previous episode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E069_inflation_the_hidden_tax.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E069_inflation_the_hidden_tax.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-07-24T13:59:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>68 Becoming Who You Are Interview Part 1</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yHI_pZok_Xg/UA6bWbqhlHI/AAAAAAAAAd4/qkXpZiEjpqM/s1600/BWYAsquare.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-yHI_pZok_Xg/UA6bWbqhlHI/AAAAAAAAAd4/qkXpZiEjpqM/s200/BWYAsquare.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;169&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This is a repost of the latest &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.becomingwhoyouare.net/2012/07/episode-009-interview-with-jake-from-the-voluntary-life-part-1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Becoming Who You Are Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, where I was interviewed by the lovely host of BWYA, my partner&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.becomingwhoyouare.net/about/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hannah&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;In Part 1 we talk about how The Voluntary Life began and about feeling free to be yourself in your friendships.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E068_BWYA_interview_part_1.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E068_BWYA_interview_part_1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-07-23T23:06:00.004+01:00</pubDate>
<title>67 Success Is The Best Revenge</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This is a short spontaneous speech by Jake taken from the Porc Therapy appearance in last week&#39;s show (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2012/07/66-porc-therapy-appearance-living-free.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;episode 66&lt;/a&gt;). It is about alternatives to political activism for getting more freedom in your life. I hope you enjoy it!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E067_success_is_the_best_revenge.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E067_success_is_the_best_revenge.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-07-17T16:37:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>66 Living Free Now: Porc Therapy Show</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CfOc4tG-uf8/T_FVQ_ObyGI/AAAAAAAAAdI/g0uWOSf5z6o/s1600/porctherapy.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CfOc4tG-uf8/T_FVQ_ObyGI/AAAAAAAAAdI/g0uWOSf5z6o/s200/porctherapy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This is a repost of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.porctherapy.com/2012/07/10/porc-therapy-2012-07-10-bonus-podcast-only-show/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;an episode of Porc Therapy&lt;/a&gt; hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.porctherapy.com/extras/host-bio/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stephanie Murphy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;that Hannah and I appeared on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;My friends Jake from &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Voluntary Life&lt;/a&gt; and Hannah from &lt;a href=&quot;http://becomingwhoyouare.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Becoming Who You Are&lt;/a&gt; join me today for this fun podcast-only show where our discussion centers around living free – now! We begin with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://freestateproject.org/content/porcfest&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PorcFest 2012&lt;/a&gt; wrap up, then talk about connecting over shared values, immigration issues, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://freestateproject.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Free State Project&lt;/a&gt;, civil disobedience and political activism (and our disagreements with both), Jake’s amazing impassioned speech on living free!, intentional communities, permanent tourism and heading south to find freedom, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wcyb.com/The-6-million-man-made-floating-island/-/14590664/15369114/-/yqoa3fz/-/index.html?treets=tric&amp;amp;tid=26512279619813&amp;amp;tml=tric_irr&amp;amp;tmi=tric_irr_1_01300107022012&amp;amp;ts=H&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;living on a boat&lt;/a&gt;, someone who made &lt;a href=&quot;http://boingboing.net/2010/09/13/gentleman-lives-on-f.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;his own island out of soda bottles&lt;/a&gt;, division of labor/going “off the grid,” and Leonid Rogozov’s famous&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leonid_Rogozov&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; self-appendectomy&lt;/a&gt;.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E066_porc_therapy_bonus_show.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E066_porc_therapy_bonus_show.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-07-16T14:58:00.002+01:00</pubDate>
<title>65 A Review of The Virtue Of Selfishness By Ayn Rand</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-umfaePYG-NQ/UAPHaPl1eTI/AAAAAAAAAds/w5oyQVefpJs/s1600/virtueofselfishness.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-umfaePYG-NQ/UAPHaPl1eTI/AAAAAAAAAds/w5oyQVefpJs/s200/virtueofselfishness.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;118&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is a review of &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0451163931/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0451163931&quot;&gt;The Virtue of Selfishness&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by Ayn Rand. It is a group discussion and the guests include &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.porctherapy.com/extras/host-bio/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Stephanie Murphy&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.porctherapy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Porc Therapy&lt;/a&gt;, freelance writer&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/gregminton&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Greg Minton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;George the expat auditor (from&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2012/06/emigrating-in-europe.html&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;episodes 58&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2012/06/59-what-happened-to-greece.html&quot; style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;59&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;and other friends. Here are some of the things we cover in the discussion:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;The book&#39;s gutsy title and the controversy surrounding it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;The pros and cons of Ayn Rand&#39;s morality and her own moralising.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;Aspects of the book we found unconvincing, such as her dismissal of voluntaryism and her idea that no conflict of interest is possible between rational people.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;Rand&#39;s convincing takedown of ethical lifeboat scenarios.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;The fact that Ayn Rand is ignored in universities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;The impact that some of Ayn Rand&#39;s contradictions (on intellectual property and on non-aggression) have had on the objectivist movement&#39;s development, especially it&#39;s pro-war stance on foreign policy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;Her deconstruction of other moral theories that were around during her time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;Plus, we have a lot of fun talking about her strange views on tapdancing and morality!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E065_virtue_of_selfishness_by_ayn_rand.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E065_virtue_of_selfishness_by_ayn_rand.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-07-11T13:05:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>64 What They Don&#39;t Teach at School Part 2</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mQKrZwH7v0E/T_1jV2uXZKI/AAAAAAAAAdg/9KrwhJpXTAg/s1600/schoolsuckssmall.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;89&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mQKrZwH7v0E/T_1jV2uXZKI/AAAAAAAAAdg/9KrwhJpXTAg/s200/schoolsuckssmall.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is a continuation of the discussion I had with &lt;a href=&quot;http://edu-lu-tion.com/contact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brett Veinotte&lt;/a&gt; about how entrepreneurship is not taught at school and why. It was recorded live for the&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://edu-lu-tion.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;School Sucks Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;http://happyporcupine.info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Porcfest&lt;/a&gt;. We talk about why it is that teachers are usually the last people who you would expect to learn entrepreneurship from and what you can do to learn it yourself. Sorry about the audio quality, it is a little choppy but still listenable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;background-color: white;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E064_what_they_dont_teach_at_school_Part_2.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E064_what_they_dont_teach_at_school_Part_2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-07-10T11:36:00.001+01:00</pubDate>
<title>63 What They Don&#39;t Teach at School: Discussion With Brett Veinotte of School Sucks</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-atSjLyhaJJI/T_v4uStcfII/AAAAAAAAAdU/BJAja5y7Yho/s1600/porcfest.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;112&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-atSjLyhaJJI/T_v4uStcfII/AAAAAAAAAdU/BJAja5y7Yho/s200/porcfest.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is part of a discussion that I had with Brett Veinotte from &lt;a href=&quot;http://edu-lu-tion.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;School Sucks Podcast&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://happyporcupine.info/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Porcfest&lt;/a&gt;. Brett and I talked about how entrepreneurship is totally alien to compulsory schooling. School prepares you for a life of working for someone else, whereas goals like working for yourself, growing a business and obtaining financial freedom are never discussed. We discuss things that you can do to overcome the conformity that school sets you up for, such as starting a business as young as possible (even whilst at school) and working to become financially independent of your parents as soon as possible. Here is a video of the full presentation, which you can also hear on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://schoolsucks.podomatic.com/entry/2012-07-06T14_03_22-07_00&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Brett&#39;s podcast for the full discussion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;266&quot; class=&quot;BLOGGER-youtube-video&quot; classid=&quot;clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000&quot; codebase=&quot;http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=6,0,40,0&quot; data-thumbnail-src=&quot;http://2.gvt0.com/vi/deKGnWNTjTI/0.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/deKGnWNTjTI&amp;fs=1&amp;source=uds&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;bgcolor&quot; value=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot; /&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot; /&gt;&lt;embed width=&quot;320&quot; height=&quot;266&quot;  src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/deKGnWNTjTI&amp;fs=1&amp;source=uds&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E063_what_they_dont_teach_at_school.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E063_what_they_dont_teach_at_school.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-07-02T09:19:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>62 What You Can Do To Live Free: Porc Therapy Interview</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CfOc4tG-uf8/T_FVQ_ObyGI/AAAAAAAAAdI/g0uWOSf5z6o/s1600/porctherapy.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CfOc4tG-uf8/T_FVQ_ObyGI/AAAAAAAAAdI/g0uWOSf5z6o/s200/porctherapy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is an interview that Jake did on the P&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.porctherapy.com/&quot;&gt;orc Therapy Podcast&lt;/a&gt;, recorded live at &lt;a href=&quot;http://happyporcupine.info/&quot;&gt;Porcfest 2012&lt;/a&gt;. In the interview, Jake talks about some of the things you can do to live more freely whatever society or economy you find yourself in, such as investing in friendships and living abroad.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E062_porctherapy_interview.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E062_porctherapy_interview.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-06-26T15:12:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>61 Entrepreneurship Makes the World a Better Place: Free Talk Live Interview</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_4_dYBnyo2w/T-nC2-r4PgI/AAAAAAAAAc8/wc9IGCGjuaQ/s1600/FTL.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_4_dYBnyo2w/T-nC2-r4PgI/AAAAAAAAAc8/wc9IGCGjuaQ/s200/FTL.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is an interview that Jake did on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freetalklive.com/&quot;&gt;Free Talk Live&lt;/a&gt; radio show. Jake talks about entrepreneurship as the best way to achieve more freedom in your life and to make the world a better place.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E061_FTL_interview.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E061_FTL_interview.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-06-18T08:00:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>60 Unschooling Year 1</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-l3OsOCzUvJQ/TklsDGJQoSI/AAAAAAAAAR4/NgYgIefGt9A/s1600/unschool3.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;103&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-l3OsOCzUvJQ/TklsDGJQoSI/AAAAAAAAAR4/NgYgIefGt9A/s200/unschool3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Matt and Molly have been unschooling their two children for a year. In this episode, they talk about their family&#39;s experiences during their first year of living as if school didn&#39;t exist. If you are interested in finding out more about unschooling check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/search/label/unschooling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the previous episodes on the topic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E060_unschooling_year_1.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E060_unschooling_year_1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-06-11T16:13:00.001+01:00</pubDate>
<title>59 What Happened To Greece?</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FbRcsoB5y9g/T9YGlFQMYkI/AAAAAAAAAcs/b7PYT1fcwoI/s1600/greece2.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;148&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FbRcsoB5y9g/T9YGlFQMYkI/AAAAAAAAAcs/b7PYT1fcwoI/s200/greece2.png&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;George is a professional auditor who grew up in Greece and emigrated to the UK. In this episode, he provides a background to the current economic crisis in Greece. He shares his thoughts on what life is like for ordinary people during the economic deflation and what the prospects are for the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E059_what_happened_to_greece.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/TVL_E059_what_happened_to_greece.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-06-06T15:56:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Emigrating in Europe</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cnHvjkd8rio/T89rrTNTuPI/AAAAAAAAAcE/mEZJRruhMXk/s1600/europe.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cnHvjkd8rio/T89rrTNTuPI/AAAAAAAAAcE/mEZJRruhMXk/s200/europe.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with George, who emigrated from Greece to resettle in the UK. George provides many suggestions that will be relevant for anyone considering emigration, even if you are not in the EU.&amp;nbsp;If you do live in the EU, it is very much worth considering the opportunities of doing what George has done and relocating to a place that might better suit your needs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/emigrating_in_europe.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/emigrating_in_europe.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-05-28T10:20:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Chris Guillebeau on &quot;The $100 Startup&quot;</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-JMrRDg86Y8s/T8M09uDM3aI/AAAAAAAAAbw/4nRtIGGVRSc/s1600/chris.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-JMrRDg86Y8s/T8M09uDM3aI/AAAAAAAAAbw/4nRtIGGVRSc/s200/chris.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is a recording of a talk given by &lt;a href=&quot;http://chrisguillebeau.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chris Guillebeau&lt;/a&gt; about his new book&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0307951529/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0307951529&quot;&gt;The 100 Dollar Startup&lt;/a&gt;. The talk took place in Shoreditch, London on 25th May 2012 and Chris kindly gave permission for me to record it for this podcast.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the talk, Chris shares some of the stories of the many &quot;solopreneurs&quot; and small business owners that he interviewed for the book, all of whom are using creative self-employment to give themselves more freedom in life.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/100_dollar_startup.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/100_dollar_startup.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-05-21T15:28:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>The Sovereign Individual by James Dale Davidson and William Rees-Mogg</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-j7_fhN1B5Ec/T7pMmxromzI/AAAAAAAAAbM/gn1BSm_Mz3c/s1600/sovereign_Individual.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-j7_fhN1B5Ec/T7pMmxromzI/AAAAAAAAAbM/gn1BSm_Mz3c/s200/sovereign_Individual.gif&quot; width=&quot;131&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode discusses ideas from the book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0684832720/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0684832720&quot;&gt;The Sovereign Individual: Mastering the Transition to the Information Age&lt;/a&gt;&quot;by James Dale Davidson and William Rees-Mogg.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;In The Sovereign Individual, Davidson and Rees-Mogg explore the greatest economic and political transition in centuries -- the shift from an industrial to an information-based society. This transition, which they have termed &quot;the fourth stage of human society,&quot; will liberate individuals as never before, irrevocably altering the power of government.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_sovereign_individual.mp3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_sovereign_individual.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-05-17T17:43:00.002+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 9: Financing Your Startup</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mFrTDGGEFq4/T7UqrB4YI7I/AAAAAAAAAa4/qfUR2ErsecA/s1600/Cash+Flow+Curve+basic.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;145&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mFrTDGGEFq4/T7UqrB4YI7I/AAAAAAAAAa4/qfUR2ErsecA/s200/Cash+Flow+Curve+basic.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How will you finance your startup? This episode presents some thoughts on the issue of financing for entrepreneurs based on my own experience, including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why bootstrapping your business with revenue finance is the best way to fund your own startup, if you can do it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The benefit of having some personal savings and no major financial commitments, if you want to start a business&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The role that loans can play in funding your venture and how taking out loans for business is a far better use of debt than taking out loans for consumption items&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why selling equity in your company (taking investment from VC or others) is ultimately a very expensive way to fund your venture&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why Business Development Grants are never &quot;free money&quot; and have serious drawbacks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The importance of looking long and hard at whether you really need the money to get going. You probably don&#39;t need nearly as much as you think&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/financing_your_business.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/financing_your_business.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-05-08T18:23:00.001+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 8: Selling Your Business</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Every entrepreneur will ultimately exit from their business, in one way or another. Unless you plan to just wind it down, one day you&#39;ll probably want to sell your company. In this podcast, Jake talks about his experience of selling a business and answers some key questions about the process, including:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why sell your business?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How do you find a buyer?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When is the right time to sell?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How do you value your business?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What happens in the negotiation process?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How long does it take?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What happens after the sale?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/selling_your_business.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/selling_your_business.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-04-30T09:32:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Freedom From School: An Interview With Laurette Lynn</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TJUMIKczy0s/T5q5MeUPN6I/AAAAAAAAAaM/orU--iZn3v8/s1600/laurette.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TJUMIKczy0s/T5q5MeUPN6I/AAAAAAAAAaM/orU--iZn3v8/s200/laurette.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with Laurette Lynn, author, speaker and host of the Unplugged Mom internet talk&amp;nbsp;show. Laurette&#39;s work emphasizes the need for families to unplug from mainstream assumptions in learning and living, disconnect from the artificial process of life and discover the freedom and joy in learning and living more authentically.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the interview she talks about freedom from school for kids and families. Laurette explains the choice that she made not to send her kids to school &quot;because they don&#39;t need it&quot;. She shares her thoughts on how you can raise your kids free from school too. &amp;nbsp;Check out the previous episodes related to &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/search/label/unschooling&quot;&gt;unschooling&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/freedom_from_school.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/freedom_from_school.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-04-23T22:02:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 7: Negotiation</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about negotiation for entrepreneurs. Some basic practical tips are provided about negotiating, such as:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The benefits of writing everything down (even though it seems obvious)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why it&#39;s better to be explicit about how you want do business, such as with a simple set of standard terms&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Negotiating about all the terms and avoiding the pitfall of focussing narrowly on price&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Some of the deeper principles underlying negotiation are also explained, such as:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The concept of your Best Alternative to a Negotiated Agreement (BATNA) and how it determines the dynamic of the negotiation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The value of appealing to objective standards and avoiding a &quot;contest of wills&quot;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why win-win negotiations are the only way to get any lasting agreement that will work&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why it makes sense to adopt the premise that you&#39;ll never be able to rely on enforcing legal contracts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;The excellent book on negotiation recommended in the podcast is &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0143118757/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0143118757&quot;&gt;Getting to Yes: Negotiating Agreement Without Giving In&lt;/a&gt;&quot; by Fischer and Ury.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/negotiation.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/negotiation.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-04-10T10:20:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Self-Publishing: An Interview With Tarrin Lupo</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PO7ex_QreLM/T4P2-yeXKDI/AAAAAAAAAZY/ODu9F61qYg0/s1600/tarrin.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-PO7ex_QreLM/T4P2-yeXKDI/AAAAAAAAAZY/ODu9F61qYg0/s200/tarrin.jpg&quot; width=&quot;199&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogger.com/%3Ca%20target=%22_blank%22%20href=%22http://www.amazon.com/mn/landing/B005CDUB3Q/?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957%22%3E&quot;&gt;Tarrin P. Lupo&lt;/a&gt;, about how he become a self-pubDate&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.LupoLit.com/&quot;&gt;author&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and how you could to. Tarrin  is best known for being the author of the historical fiction series &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004Q3RL6I/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004Q3RL6I&quot;&gt;Pirates of Savannah&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and his children&#39;s book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005CF7BY6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B005CF7BY6&quot;&gt;Catch That Collie&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. He has successfully pubDate thirteen eBooks and short stories. He is also a liberty activist who runs a news service called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/user/LCLREPORT&quot;&gt;The Low Country Liberty Report&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and co-hosts the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wheelsoffliberty.podomatic.com/&quot;&gt;Wheels off Liberty&lt;/a&gt; podcast. He currently resides in Savannah Georgia and is a member of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://freestateproject.org/&quot;&gt;Free State Project&lt;/a&gt;, spending time in New Hampshire promoting the ideas of Freedom and Liberty.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the interview Tarrin explains the difference between self-publishing and traditional routes to publishing for authors. He talks about the business of self-publishing and provides guidance on how to successfully market your work. He shares his thoughts on the skill of writing and on what it takes to write commercially. He also provides his views about intellectual property and the publishing industry and his thoughts about where the industry is going.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/self_publishing.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/self_publishing.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-04-03T09:39:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Financial Preparedness: An Interview With Medium Tex</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FA3PXfteq3I/T3q2-2K6ZBI/AAAAAAAAAZE/SgGBqKGqDAw/s1600/Umbrella.png&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FA3PXfteq3I/T3q2-2K6ZBI/AAAAAAAAAZE/SgGBqKGqDAw/s200/Umbrella.png&quot; width=&quot;193&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;This episode is an interview with Mike&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;,&amp;nbsp;one of the moderators and main contributors to &lt;a href=&quot;http://gyroscopicinvesting.com/forum/&quot;&gt;the Permanent Portfolio discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;. Mike, or &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gyroscopicinvesting.com/forum/index.php?action=profile;u=17&quot;&gt;Medium Tex&lt;/a&gt;&quot; as he is known on the board, is an independent investor and co-author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://crawlingroad.com/blog/2012/01/03/a-new-permanent-portfolio-book-is-on-the-way/&quot;&gt;an upcoming book&lt;/a&gt; on the permanent portfolio approach to investment. In the interview Mike explains a simple way of understanding all the different economic conditions we might face and how to be financially prepared for any of them as a private investor.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You can get more information about the concept of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fail-Safe_Investing#The_Permanent_Portfolio&quot;&gt;permanent portfolio&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2010/05/investing-for-financial-freedom-two.html&quot;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.co.uk/2012/02/investing-in-europe-interview-with-marc.html&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;previous podcast episodes, in&amp;nbsp;Harry Browne&#39;s book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031226321X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=031226321X&quot;&gt;Fail-Safe Investing&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gyroscopicinvesting.com/forum&quot;&gt;permanent portfolio forum&lt;/a&gt; and on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://crawlingroad.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Crawling Road &lt;/a&gt;website.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/financial_preparedness.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/financial_preparedness.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-03-26T08:27:00.001+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Author Interview: Jeffrey Tucker on &quot;It&#39;s A Jetsons World&quot;</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Jao_qn5wWgE/T29Xv-qkivI/AAAAAAAAAYo/XSEfZkJVCCc/s1600/jetson.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Jao_qn5wWgE/T29Xv-qkivI/AAAAAAAAAYo/XSEfZkJVCCc/s200/jetson.jpg&quot; width=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with Jeffrey Tucker about his latest book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1610161947/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1610161947&quot;&gt;It&#39;s a Jetsons World: Private Miracles and Public Crimes&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&amp;nbsp;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://mises.org/document/6528&quot;&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt; for free).&amp;nbsp;Jeffrey is the executive editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lfb.org/&quot;&gt;Laissez Faire Books.&lt;/a&gt; He is past editorial vice president of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mises.org/&quot;&gt;Ludwig von Mises Institute&lt;/a&gt; and past editor for the institute&#39;s website, &lt;a href=&quot;http://Mises.org/&quot;&gt;Mises.org&lt;/a&gt;. He is also an adjunct scholar with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mackinac.org/&quot;&gt;Mackinac Center for Public Policy&lt;/a&gt; and an &lt;a href=&quot;http://university.acton.org/&quot;&gt;Acton University&lt;/a&gt; faculty member.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1610161947/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1610161947&quot;&gt;It&#39;s a Jetsons World&lt;/a&gt;&quot; is about how we are surrounded by miracles created in the private sector, particularly in the digital universe, and yet we don&#39;t appreciate them enough. Meanwhile, the public sector is systematically wrecking the physical world in sneaky and petty ways that really do matter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jeffrey discusses these themes further in the interview, such as the global communication revolution that we are living through and it&#39;s amazing impact on all our lives. He also talks about the destructive role that the State is having during this time of great progress.&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&quot;We are very fortunate to be living in a social, cultural and economic transition that makes the industrial revolution look like nothing by comparison. The amazing irony is that it is happening exactly at the same time when Leviathan, at least in the developed world, is on the march as never before&quot;. &lt;/i&gt;Jeffrey Tucker (from the interview)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;He discusses some of the ideas from the book in more detail, such as the negative impact of Intellectual Property law and the moral hazard that it creates, as IP corrupts the outlook of entrepreneurs. &amp;nbsp;The interview is full of Jeffrey&#39;s brilliantly optimistic and positive outlook.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;We shouldn&#39;t be afraid to read things that are utterly contrary to what think we believe, because it&#39;s only going to strengthen us. If we are fearless intellectuals, which we should all be- to the point where we are utterly fearless, then we shouldn&#39;t be afraid of any writer, any genre or any political point of view. It just makes us better thinkers.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Jeffrey Tucker (from the interview)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Show Notes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0071747044/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0071747044&quot;&gt;The Birth of Plenty: How the Prosperity of the Modern World was Created&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0033AGSTQ/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0033AGSTQ&quot;&gt;A Splendid Exchange: How Trade Shaped the World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0691003815/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0691003815&quot;&gt;The Ultimate Resource 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steve Jobs: &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CW0DUg63lqU&quot;&gt;we have always been shameless about stealing great ideas&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/jeffrey_tucker_its_a_jetsons_world.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/jeffrey_tucker_its_a_jetsons_world.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-03-19T08:33:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 6: Getting Things Done</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-xWoplWhnqoM/T2Y69bnyBKI/AAAAAAAAAYM/BDigmMKxz74/s1600/GTD.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;167&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-xWoplWhnqoM/T2Y69bnyBKI/AAAAAAAAAYM/BDigmMKxz74/s200/GTD.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;A podcast about freeing your mind to get things done. A big challenge with&amp;nbsp;time management and productivity that I experienced was how to&amp;nbsp;overcome that feeling of being overwhelmed. &amp;nbsp;How do you free your mind from the nagging thoughts of all the things that you need to do, so that you can get on with actually doing stuff?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this podcast I discuss my journey through trying many approaches to time management and the value that I found in David Allen&#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0142000280/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0142000280&quot;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(GTD) approach. Unlike traditional personal productivity systems,&amp;nbsp;GTD helps you harnesses the creativity and intuitive power of your unconscious to work with you, rather than interrupt you.&amp;nbsp;I outline what I think are the most helpful concepts in the GTD approach and how it might help you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/getting_things_done.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/getting_things_done.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-03-12T18:16:00.001+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Investing In Friendships</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;When it comes to friendships, are you investing wisely?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/investing_in_friendships.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/investing_in_friendships.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-03-05T13:27:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Investing in Gold and Silver</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-0RH553f3MS4/TfeNGnMRx3I/AAAAAAAAAQs/Nwj6UnQ1hrE/s1600/gold.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-0RH553f3MS4/TfeNGnMRx3I/AAAAAAAAAQs/Nwj6UnQ1hrE/s200/gold.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Meet the gold bugs! An international discussion among friends who all invest in precious metals. The discussion covers some important questions that all private investors face:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Which do you invest in, gold or silver? If you hold both, do you have a strategy as to how much gold vs silver you hold?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What percentage of your overall portfolio do precious metals have?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;How will you know when to sell your precious metals?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In the discussion we refer to the book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0446510998/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0446510998&quot;&gt;Guide to Investing In Gold and Silver&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Michael Maloney.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/investing_in_gold_and_silver.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/investing_in_gold_and_silver.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-02-27T08:00:00.019+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 5: The Unexamined Business Is Not Worth Building</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about the amazing value that comes from tracking your business. Whereas &#39;business plans&#39; are really just &#39;business guesses&#39; and can often be a waste of time, tracking the reality of your business is always incredibly useful. The data that you have about each aspect of your business (your sales opportunities, your contacts, your&amp;nbsp;cash-flow&amp;nbsp;and many other aspects) is the most valuable asset that you have.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_unexamined_business.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_unexamined_business.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-02-20T08:00:00.018+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Living And Parenting Free Of Religion: An Interview With Carisa Brewster</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-xpn84e2ytoQ/T0FIQk0sbfI/AAAAAAAAAX0/8b7EW9X856Y/s1600/Carisa.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;160&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-xpn84e2ytoQ/T0FIQk0sbfI/AAAAAAAAAX0/8b7EW9X856Y/s200/Carisa.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with Carisa Brewster, author of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blog.carisabrewster.com/&quot;&gt;Cup of Curiosity&lt;/a&gt; blog. Carisa describes herself as a writer, mom and nappy chick with way too many interests. In this interview she talks about the experience of breaking free from religion and choosing to parent and unschool her children free from any religion. Her blog covers many diverse topics from books, natural hair, living in Oregon, interracial issues, breastfeeding/parenting and pop culture. She is also a (self-confessed) huge Star Wars and Star Trek geek, but only a moderate comic book geek. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/living_and_parenting_free_of_religion.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/living_and_parenting_free_of_religion.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-02-13T07:00:00.005+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Investing In Europe: An Interview With Marc De Mesel</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about investing inside the Euro zone as an independent individual investor. It is an interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marcdemesel.be/&quot;&gt;Marc de Mesel&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;who runs a blog on&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.marcdemesel.be/&quot;&gt; investing in Europe in dutch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://europeanpermanentportfolio.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;also an investing blog&amp;nbsp;in english&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Marc talks about his experience applying the Permanent Portfolio strategy in a European context. He also provides his thoughts on speculating in gold and other precious metals. The episode is provided as food for thought to encourage critical thinking and independent decision-making in regard to investment: it is opinion only and should not be considered any kind of financial advice.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For more information about the concept of the permanent portfolio see Harry Browne&#39;s book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/031226321X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=031226321X&quot;&gt;Fail-Safe Investing&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. You can also hear more about the Permanent Portfolio concept in &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.com/2010/05/investing-for-financial-freedom-two.html&quot;&gt;this previous episode&lt;/a&gt;. The book that Marc mentions in the episode is &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/9628606727/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=9628606727&quot;&gt;Tomorrow&#39;s Gold&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;Mark Farber.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/investing_in_europe.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/investing_in_europe.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-02-06T11:36:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Author Interview: Paul Rosenberg on A Lodging of Wayfaring Men Part 2</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Part 2 of the interview with Paul Rosenberg about his novel &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/097960110X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=097960110X&quot;&gt;A Lodging of Wayfaring Men&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. Paul shares his thoughts on many of the other themes covered in the novel: sexuality, relationships, the unconscious mind and religion. He explains his view on intellectual property and why he chose to release the novel using the creative commons license. He also gives an insight into&amp;nbsp;his upcoming books.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/a_lodging_of_wayfaring_men_2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/a_lodging_of_wayfaring_men_2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-01-31T08:29:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Author Interview: Paul Rosenberg on A Lodging of Wayfaring Men Part 1</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4qqdwewUGSQ/TybG1FognBI/AAAAAAAAAXk/D1SGrHltx_Y/s1600/lodging.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-4qqdwewUGSQ/TybG1FognBI/AAAAAAAAAXk/D1SGrHltx_Y/s200/lodging.jpg&quot; width=&quot;146&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This Part 1 of an interview with Paul Rosenberg, author of &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/097960110X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=097960110X&quot;&gt;A Lodging of Wayfaring Men&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;Instantly named Freedom Book of The Month and a major influence in the Cyber-underground, A Lodging of Wayfaring Men is the story of freedom-seekers who create an alternative society on the Internet - a virtual society, with no possibility of oversight or control. It grows so fast that governments and &quot;leaders&quot; are terrified, and fight to co-opt this cyber-society before it undermines the power of the governing elite.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this interview Paul talks about his intellectual development, his influences and the background to writing the book. He discusses the parallels between the novel and recent developments in crypto-currency, such as Bitcoin. He shares his thoughts on the current state of the internet, prospects for liberty and the potential for developing communities of people with shared values.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/a_lodging_of_wayfaring_men_1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/a_lodging_of_wayfaring_men_1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-01-24T01:37:00.001+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Financial Independence from Parents</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is about the freedom&amp;nbsp;in adult life&amp;nbsp;that is gained by achieving financial independence from parents. Jake talks about some of the findings of the book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1589795474/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1589795474&quot;&gt;The Millionaire Next Door&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Thomas Stanley. Dr Stanley surveyed people in America who had become millionaires within one generation and collected data on many aspects of their lives. &amp;nbsp;One finding that he identified was that adult-children who continue to receive economic&amp;nbsp;subsidies from their parents tend to be much less successful in developing wealth within their own lives. Those who don&#39;t receive &quot;economic out-patient care&quot; end up wealthier and also have better relationships with their parents.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/financial_independence.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/financial_independence.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-01-16T18:02:00.001+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 4: Profit is Sanity</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;A podcast for entrepreneurs about getting your business to profitability and making it more and more profitable once you get there. The title of this podcast comes from the saying &quot;turnover is vanity and profit is sanity&quot;. Some of the topics covered in the episode include:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;The unjustly-bad reputation that profit has in our culture and it&#39;s origins&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The other&amp;nbsp;motives (unrelated to profit) that entrepreneurs have and the problems that they cause for their business&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Profit as the truly rational measure of how healthy your business is&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Two approaches cutting expenses to increase profit&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The value of measuring profitability at the project or product level&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The necessity of measuring all aspects of operations to find out where you make a profit and where you don&#39;t&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/profit_is_sanity.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/profit_is_sanity.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-01-11T18:25:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 3: In Praise Of Selling</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;In this podcast, Jake talks about the most important responsibility you will ever have as an entrepreneur: selling. He talks about how to overcome the barriers to selling that most entrepreneurs face: &amp;nbsp;the cultural prejudice against sales, ignorance about what selling really is and the psychological barrier to selling (the fear of rejection).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stages of Selling To Learn More About:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prospecting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Contacting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Qualifying&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Presentation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Handling Objections&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Closing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Referrals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Checklist for New Entrepreneurs:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ol style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have you started selling yet?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are you setting aside specific time within each day or week devoted only to selling?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are you measuring everything that you can measure about your selling activity?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Show Notes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00005JKG9/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00005JKG9&quot;&gt;Glengarry Glen Ross&lt;/a&gt; (great movie, but also an example of how negative the representation of selling is in our culture)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0446692743/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0446692743&quot;&gt;How to Master the Art of Selling&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Tom Hopkins (a recommended book).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/in_praise_of_selling.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/in_praise_of_selling.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2012-01-02T09:00:00.002+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Psychological Freedom: An Interview With Daniel Mackler</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1N6l-lV6wE8/TusT5db65OI/AAAAAAAAAXI/IOCu0ZFl9jg/s1600/daniel.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-1N6l-lV6wE8/TusT5db65OI/AAAAAAAAAXI/IOCu0ZFl9jg/s200/daniel.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with psychologist and filmmaker &lt;a href=&quot;http://iraresoul.com/&quot;&gt;Daniel Mackler&lt;/a&gt; about the subject of psychological freedom. Daniel shares his thoughts on what psychological freedom means: the healing from past psychological traumas. He identifies the root of trauma in unhealthy parenting and talks about his own journey towards more psychological freedom. &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/psychological_freedom.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/psychological_freedom.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-12-26T09:00:00.021+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Freedom From Politics Part 2</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-GxYlHA7xL00/TujEeIXVhkI/AAAAAAAAAW0/epmQ16rnlqk/s1600/tumblr_ln3mghgmG71qzdeuxo1_500.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-GxYlHA7xL00/TujEeIXVhkI/AAAAAAAAAW0/epmQ16rnlqk/s200/tumblr_ln3mghgmG71qzdeuxo1_500.jpg&quot; width=&quot;126&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part 2 in a series of episodes on freedom from politics with special guest Stephanie Murphy, host of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.porctherapy.com/&quot;&gt;Porc Therapy podcast&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;Show Notes:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/m/mohandasga131253.html&quot;&gt;&quot;You must be the change you wish to see in the world&quot;&lt;/a&gt; by&amp;nbsp;Gandhi&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://edition.cnn.com/2011/OPINION/08/16/jillette.atheist.libertarian/index.html&quot;&gt;Penn Gillette on politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wVETpxsEIys&quot;&gt;School Sucks Podcast on Ron Paul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xIraCchPDhk&quot;&gt;George Carlin on Not Voting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UL5MgKJ_CBs&quot;&gt;Doug Stanhope on Democracy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thinkexist.com/quotation/if_voting_changed_anything-they-d_make_it_illegal/204480.html&quot;&gt;&quot;If Voting Changed Anything They&#39;d Make it Illegal&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by&amp;nbsp;Emma Goldman&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://portfolio.willmoyer.com/post/7762224687/i-so-rarely-read-american-political-news-i-didnt&quot;&gt;Poster by Will Moyer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/freedom_from_politics_2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/freedom_from_politics_2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-12-19T09:00:00.049+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Freedom From Politics Part 1</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6K145D01Ay0/TujLl3WhOGI/AAAAAAAAAW8/yVB41dsViYE/s320/stephanie.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-6K145D01Ay0/TujLl3WhOGI/AAAAAAAAAW8/yVB41dsViYE/s200/stephanie.jpg&quot; width=&quot;135&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part 1 in a series of episodes on freedom from politics. Special guest is Stephanie Murphy, host of the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.porctherapy.com/&quot;&gt; Porc Therapy podcast&lt;/a&gt;, co-host of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freetalklive.com/&quot;&gt;Free Talk Live&lt;/a&gt; and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://flamingfreedom.com/&quot;&gt;Prometheus Unchained&lt;/a&gt;, all of which are on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://lrn.fm/&quot;&gt;Liberty Radio Network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Show Notes:&lt;br /&gt;Hans Herman Hoppe on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=heXb2zSO0Ww&quot;&gt;Marxist and Austrian Class Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Harry Browne&#39;s book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0965603679/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0965603679&quot;&gt;How I Found Freedom In An Unfree World&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stephanie&#39;s book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004JZWYLA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004JZWYLA&quot;&gt;Ron Paul: A Life of Ideas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freedomainradio.com/&quot;&gt;Freedomain Radio&lt;/a&gt; podcast&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://completeliberty.com/magazine.html&quot;&gt;Complete Liberty Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/freedom_from_politics_1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/freedom_from_politics_1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-12-12T23:59:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Unjobbing: Author Interview with Michael Fogler</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FhAwjYaXuCs/TuDInl98knI/AAAAAAAAAWk/KF63RTEp2Jo/s1600/michaelfogler.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FhAwjYaXuCs/TuDInl98knI/AAAAAAAAAWk/KF63RTEp2Jo/s200/michaelfogler.jpg&quot; width=&quot;108&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is an interview with&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://michaelfogler.com/&quot;&gt;Michael Fogler&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;about his book&amp;nbsp;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/096548341X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=096548341X&quot;&gt;Un-Jobbing: The Adult Liberation Handbook&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. Michael talks about his life experience, having reached the age of 58 without ever having had a single, full-time job. He talks about how his personal experience in &quot;failures&quot; a traditional career-job route led him to discover unjobbing as an alternative approach. He talks about how he came up with the name &quot;unjobbing&quot; and the influences on his ideas, such as Grace Llwellyn&#39;s book&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0962959170/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0962959170&quot;&gt;&quot;A Teenage Liberation Handbook&quot;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Michael provides some tips on achieving personal liberation, including the issue of minimising expenses, saving and ensuring that you &quot;act your wage&quot;. He talks about the importance of having other people around you who share your values, especially as the unjobbing approach is not considered &quot;normal&quot; by mainstream culture.&amp;nbsp;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.blogspot.com/search/label/unjobbing&quot;&gt;our previous episodes on Unjobbing&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/unjobbing_interview_with_michael_fogler.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/unjobbing_interview_with_michael_fogler.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-12-05T08:28:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Parent-Free By Choice: An Interview with Vickie Bergman</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/262806_917153988947_5615723_42873523_3238123_n.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;153&quot; src=&quot;https://fbcdn-sphotos-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/262806_917153988947_5615723_42873523_3238123_n.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;Vickie is the author of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://demandeuphoria.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Demand Euphoria&lt;/a&gt; Blog and &lt;a href=&quot;http://parentfreebychoice.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Parent-Free By Choice &lt;/a&gt;Blog. In this interview we discuss the concept of &quot;Parent-Free By Choice&quot;, which is the choice of some adults to voluntarily separate from one or both parents. Vicky talks about why this choice, although quite widespread, is viewed as a taboo subject.&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Vickie shares her thoughts on&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&quot;Apple-style-span&quot;&gt;whether or not adults who choose to cease contact with their parents are &quot;running away&quot; from issues that they should stay and face up to:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;There is this whole stigma about &quot;running away from your problems&quot;. It starts with kids and bullying in school where everyone says running away from a bully doesn&#39;t do anything, you have to stick in there and face it. That carries over into our family relationships: this idea that &quot;no matter what they do to you they are still your family&quot; and you are supposed to toughen up, figure it out, forgive or whatever. I think that is unfortunate because it allows people to keep treating each other badly. I think running away from somebody who is treating you badly is actually a good thing because you deserve better and you shouldn&#39;t put up with it. I think removing yourself from a toxic situation is good for you.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here are Vickie&#39;s thoughts on the question of whether people owe their parents anything:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;I have often thought about this concept of your parents giving you the &quot;gift of life&quot;, but I always think about that word gift and think about how...if it is truly a gift then you don&#39;t owe them for it. If they gave you a gift then they shouldn&#39;t be charging you for it every day of &amp;nbsp;your life. A lot of parents call it a gift and then make you feel guilty for everything they do for you.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vickie&#39;s blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://parentfreebychoice.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Parent-Free by Choice&lt;/a&gt;, offers a supportive environment for people to anonymously share their own stories about their choices. As Vickie explains;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;No matter what happened to them in childhood or how their relationship [with their parents] is now, if they feel like it&#39;s not a positive relationship then that is all that matters and they should have the freedom to get out of it.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/parent_free_by_choice.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/parent_free_by_choice.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-11-28T08:46:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Uncollege: An Interview with Dale Stephens</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BtcVNdHjAvQ/Ts91XpVlE5I/AAAAAAAAAWc/bse43vfRkFc/s1600/dale.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;193&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-BtcVNdHjAvQ/Ts91XpVlE5I/AAAAAAAAAWc/bse43vfRkFc/s200/dale.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with &lt;a href=&quot;http://dalejstephens.com/&quot;&gt;Dale Stephens&lt;/a&gt;, founder of the&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uncollege.org/&quot;&gt; Uncollege &lt;/a&gt;movement. Uncollege represents a revolutionary approach to education: applying the principles of unschooling to higher education. In the interview Dale talks about opportunities to hack your education and go for self-directed learning. He challenges the notion that going to college is the only path to success and identifies the declining value proposition of traditional college education, as well as the potential of an alternative, self-directed approach.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/uncollege.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/uncollege.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-11-21T16:03:00.002+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Living and Working Abroad</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-DzWkPhJaR44/Tsp-1jWTDUI/AAAAAAAAAWM/Tm4FgpBAraA/s1600/china.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;140&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-DzWkPhJaR44/Tsp-1jWTDUI/AAAAAAAAAWM/Tm4FgpBAraA/s200/china.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This episode is about how living and working abroad can bring more freedom into your life. Special guest on this episode is Jaime, a freelance writer living in Beijing. Jaime is the author of the blog&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.itsalwayssunnyinsouthkorea.com/&quot;&gt;It&#39;s Always Sunny in &lt;strike&gt;South Korea&lt;/strike&gt; Beijing&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and is one of the co-authors of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chinarchy.com/&quot;&gt;Chinarchy podcast and blog network&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/living_and_working_abroad.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/living_and_working_abroad.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-11-14T08:38:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>The Fear of Freedom by Eric Fromm</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EGblUO_amYE/Tr0GN7hpNtI/AAAAAAAAAV0/bwyftac1Rwo/s1600/fromm.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-EGblUO_amYE/Tr0GN7hpNtI/AAAAAAAAAV0/bwyftac1Rwo/s200/fromm.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode explores the topic of psychological barriers to personal and political freedom. It is a discussion of the ideas in Eric Fromm&#39;s book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0805031499/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=217145&amp;amp;creative=399369&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0805031499&quot;&gt;The Fear of Freedom&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&amp;nbsp;(also pubDate under the title &quot;Escape from Freedom&quot;). &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/fear_of_freedom.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/fear_of_freedom.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-11-07T08:48:00.003+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Successful Entrepreneurship: An Interview With Judd Weiss</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-VAleLzNtra4/TrLGqc0adtI/AAAAAAAAAUY/4j-yRQkaVKY/s1600/juddweiss.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;132&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-VAleLzNtra4/TrLGqc0adtI/AAAAAAAAAUY/4j-yRQkaVKY/s200/juddweiss.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;An interview with Judd Weiss, entrepreneur and author of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://Hustlebear.com/&quot;&gt;Hustlebear.com&lt;/a&gt; blog. Judd has been an entrepreneur since he was 14. He became a millionaire by the age of 24 and has launched successful businesses in diverse industries including selling watches online, commercial real estate brokerage and parking. Judd talks about some of the principles behind successful entrepreneurship. Topics include:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;How accepting that you start out both ignorant and incompetent can help you succeed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why success normally comes just after the point when most people quit&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Why you don&#39;t have to be interested in the product you are selling&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What a young startup entrepreneur can use to differentiate themselves from much older and better connected competitors&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The impact that pursuing entrepreneurial success can have on your personal relationships&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/successful_entrepreneurship.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/successful_entrepreneurship.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-10-31T17:03:00.001+00:00</pubDate>
<title>How To Get Financial Freedom</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;Financial Freedom is an achievable goal. But what exactly is it and how does making financial freedom your goal differ from more traditional financial goals? A common approach to personal finance goes something like this:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;MAINSTREAM ASSUMPTIONS ABOUT PERSONAL FINANCE&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;the goal of personal finance strategies is material wealth and comfort;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the method is getting a secure job;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the measure of how well you are doing is your salary;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;debt should be used, with caution, to obtain consumption items (mortgage for a house, loans for a new car etc.);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;provision for the future should be made through a pension.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A approach aimed at financial freedom is completely different in every way:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;ASSUMPTIONS WITH FINANCIAL FREEDOM AS YOUR AIM&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;the goal of personal finance strategies is financial freedom (the level of wealth is optional);&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the method is entrepreneurship;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the measure of how well you are doing is how long before you have to work again, where &lt;i&gt;passive income&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;i&gt;expenses&lt;/i&gt; &amp;gt; 0&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;debt should not be used for consumption items, but might optionally be used with caution to further entrepreneurship and value generation;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;provision for the future is made through creating passive income streams.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thoughts on how to adopt financial freedom as your goal are provided in the podcast. The views expressed are only my opinion about this subject and I am not any kind of financial advisor. Podcast &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/how_to_get_financial_freedom.mp3&quot;&gt;Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/how_to_get_financial_freedom.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-10-28T12:16:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Getting More Freedom In Your Job</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-twUi8Va5I6s/TqqKt3ZJD-I/AAAAAAAAATM/AoYiJ320zHw/s1600/freedomwork.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;99&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-twUi8Va5I6s/TqqKt3ZJD-I/AAAAAAAAATM/AoYiJ320zHw/s320/freedomwork.gif&quot; width=&quot;320&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;You can still have a lot of freedom if you are working for somebody else. Here are some suggestions of what you can do to transform your job and liberate yourself. The youtube documentary about a Brazilian company that is mentioned in the episode is called &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gG3HPX0D2mU&quot;&gt;The Caring Capitalist&lt;/a&gt;&quot;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/gettingmorefreedominyourjob.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/gettingmorefreedominyourjob.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-09-14T13:25:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 2: The Art of The Start</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-r7wmqPVA0kE/Tm96obpgCyI/AAAAAAAAASo/XuH3AJu-J44/s1600/the_art_of_the_start.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-r7wmqPVA0kE/Tm96obpgCyI/AAAAAAAAASo/XuH3AJu-J44/s200/the_art_of_the_start.jpg&quot; width=&quot;131&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This episode is a discussion with startup entrepreneurs including the founders of &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://choreplan.com/&quot;&gt;choreplan.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://knowitapp.com/&quot;&gt;knowitapp.com&lt;/a&gt;. We talk about the ideas in two great books on entrepreneurship:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Art-Start-Time-Tested-Battle-Hardened-Starting/dp/1591840562?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Art of the Start&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Guy Kawasaki and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Rework-Jason-Fried/dp/0307463745?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0307463745&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson. &lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/entrepreneurship2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/entrepreneurship2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-09-13T15:20:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Entrepreneurship Part 1: The Real Revolutionaries</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TfCHk9TvMv4/Tm9h8Ue8BRI/AAAAAAAAASk/CvOUKZpA68k/s1600/entrepreneur.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;124&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-TfCHk9TvMv4/Tm9h8Ue8BRI/AAAAAAAAASk/CvOUKZpA68k/s200/entrepreneur.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;A podcast for those considering starting a business.&amp;nbsp;The episode starts with a look at the value of entrepreneurship as a path to obtaining freedom in your own life and some background to my own experience with entrepreneurship.&amp;nbsp;Two key questions are addressed: how do you choose which project to pursue as a new entrepreneurial venture? Also, how do you overcome the fear of getting started?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/entrepreneurship1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/entrepreneurship1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-07-23T23:39:00.002+01:00</pubDate>
<title>The Voluntary City Part 3: The Future</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jSCK-uUPXMQ/TmdXt9hxHTI/AAAAAAAAASg/HiIPSYjE4ik/s1600/city3.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;132&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-jSCK-uUPXMQ/TmdXt9hxHTI/AAAAAAAAASg/HiIPSYjE4ik/s200/city3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part 3 in a series on&amp;nbsp;about the potential for voluntary, free market solutions to urban planning problems.&amp;nbsp;In this episode we discuss the potential for more voluntary kinds of urban communities, urbanisation in the developing world and&amp;nbsp;the future of cities.&amp;nbsp;The discussion is based around ideas presented in the book&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Voluntary-City-Choice-Community-Society/dp/1598130323?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Voluntary City: Choice, Community, and Civil Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1598130323&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;edited by David T Beito, Peter Gordon and Alexander Tabarrok. Special guests in this episode are Peter Gordon (co-editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Voluntary-City-Choice-Community-Society/dp/1598130323?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Voluntary City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1598130323&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;) and Adam, Stephen and Emily, who are the authors of the blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketurbanism.com/&quot;&gt;Market Urbanism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_voluntary_city3.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_voluntary_city3.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-07-23T22:00:00.004+01:00</pubDate>
<title>The Voluntary City Part 2: Voluntary Land Use Planning</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BnC87eka64o/TmXUaHjUGnI/AAAAAAAAASc/AztqF5LP1oc/s1600/110844958116.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;132&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-BnC87eka64o/TmXUaHjUGnI/AAAAAAAAASc/AztqF5LP1oc/s200/110844958116.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part 2 of a series about the potential for voluntary, free market solutions to urban planning problems.&amp;nbsp;In this episode we discuss the potential for voluntary land use planning.&amp;nbsp;The discussion is based around ideas presented in the book&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Voluntary-City-Choice-Community-Society/dp/1598130323?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Voluntary City: Choice, Community, and Civil Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1598130323&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;edited by David T Beito, Peter Gordon and Alexander Tabarrok. Special guests in this episode are Peter Gordon (co-editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Voluntary-City-Choice-Community-Society/dp/1598130323?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Voluntary City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1598130323&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;) and Adam, Stephen and Emily, who are the authors of the blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketurbanism.com/&quot;&gt;Market Urbanism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_voluntary_city2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_voluntary_city2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-07-23T21:38:00.005+01:00</pubDate>
<title>The Voluntary City Part 1: Introduction</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OyLvCC1i2eY/Tl6gXwhssaI/AAAAAAAAASQ/0eMe1V28pJI/s1600/voluntary+city2.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-OyLvCC1i2eY/Tl6gXwhssaI/AAAAAAAAASQ/0eMe1V28pJI/s200/voluntary+city2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;133&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This is the first of a series about the potential for voluntary, free market solutions to urban planning problems. This discussion is based around the topics covered in the book&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Voluntary-City-Choice-Community-Society/dp/1598130323?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Voluntary City: Choice, Community, and Civil Society&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1598130323&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;edited by David T Beito, Peter Gordon and Alexander Tabarrok. Special guests in this episode are Peter Gordon (co-editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Voluntary-City-Choice-Community-Society/dp/1598130323?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Voluntary City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1598130323&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;) and Adam, Stephen and Emily, who are the authors of the blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketurbanism.com/&quot;&gt;Market Urbanism&lt;/a&gt;. In the discussion we make reference to Jane Jacobs, author of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Death-Great-American-Cities-Anniversary/dp/0679644334?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Death and Life of Great American Cities&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and to Robert Moses, the urban planner who&#39;s destructive impact is discussed in the book&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Power-Broker-Robert-Moses-Fall/dp/0394720245?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Power Broker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_voluntary_city1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/the_voluntary_city1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-06-25T21:00:00.001+01:00</pubDate>
<title>The Moon is a Harsh Mistress by Robert Heinlein</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_g1CCFVLBFQ/TlP5NwbQ62I/AAAAAAAAASM/hd_VKsDCbBk/s1600/heinlein.jpeg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-_g1CCFVLBFQ/TlP5NwbQ62I/AAAAAAAAASM/hd_VKsDCbBk/s200/heinlein.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;123&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;A review of Robert Heinlein&#39;s libertarian science fiction novel, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Moon-Harsh-Mistress-Robert-Heinlein/dp/0312863551?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Moon Is a Harsh Mistress&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0312863551&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/moon_is_a_harsh_mistress.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/moon_is_a_harsh_mistress.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-03-26T22:54:00.024+00:00</pubDate>
<title>We the Living by Ayn Rand</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jNpbS_uQ6bk/TlIN5hyFL1I/AAAAAAAAASE/a4zNT9hxyW0/s1600/we+the+living.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jNpbS_uQ6bk/TlIN5hyFL1I/AAAAAAAAASE/a4zNT9hxyW0/s200/we+the+living.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;A discussion of Ayn Rand&#39;s semi-autobiographical novel &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/We-Living-75th-Anniversary-Deluxe/dp/0451233263?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;We the Living&lt;/a&gt;. pubDate in 1936, &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/We-Living-75th-Anniversary-Deluxe/dp/0451233263?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;We the Living&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;was the first&amp;nbsp;novel&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;to emerge in the West that&amp;nbsp;described life in Russia during the communist revolution of 1917 and was written&amp;nbsp;by someone who experienced it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/we_the_living.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/we_the_living.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-02-26T23:41:00.018+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Unschooling Part 3: Putting Unschooling Into Practice</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-l3OsOCzUvJQ/TklsDGJQoSI/AAAAAAAAAR4/NgYgIefGt9A/s1600/unschool3.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;103&quot; src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-l3OsOCzUvJQ/TklsDGJQoSI/AAAAAAAAAR4/NgYgIefGt9A/s200/unschool3.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part 3 in a series on unschooling. This episode is about implementing an unschooling approach. Special guests are Brett Veinotte, host of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://schoolsucks.podomatic.com/&quot;&gt;School Sucks Podcast&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;Stefan Molyneux, host of &lt;a href=&quot;http://freedomainradio.com/&quot;&gt;Freedomain Radio&lt;/a&gt; and Debbie Harbeson, unschooling parent and author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.debbieharbeson.com/Blog/&quot;&gt;&quot;OK Kids, Time for Bedlam&quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/unschooling3.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/unschooling3.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-02-26T23:00:00.000+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Unschooling Part 2: The Compulsory Education System</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-wtypQ7cADQI/Tke3HtvzFWI/AAAAAAAAAR0/dswBAPqN_F8/s1600/unschool2.gif&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-wtypQ7cADQI/Tke3HtvzFWI/AAAAAAAAAR0/dswBAPqN_F8/s200/unschool2.gif&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;Part 2 in a series on Unschooling. Special guests are Brett Veinotte, host of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://schoolsucks.podomatic.com/&quot;&gt;School Sucks Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Stefan Molyneux, host of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://freedomainradio.com/&quot;&gt;Freedomain Radio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-top: 0px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/unschooling2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/unschooling2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-02-26T22:52:00.040+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Unschooling Part 1: Instead of Education</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-0SjKNZW8ddA/Tka0ITp_HaI/AAAAAAAAARw/SRCQYSzpDsE/s1600/insteadofed.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-0SjKNZW8ddA/Tka0ITp_HaI/AAAAAAAAARw/SRCQYSzpDsE/s200/insteadofed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;130&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part one of a series of podcasts on &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unschooling&quot;&gt;Unschooling&lt;/a&gt;. This episode is a discussion of one of the most influential books about unschooling: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Instead-Education-People-Things-Better/dp/1591810094?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instead of Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=1591810094&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;by John Holt. Special guests are Brett Veinotte, host of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://schoolsucks.podomatic.com/&quot;&gt;School Sucks Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and Stefan Molyneux, host of &lt;a href=&quot;http://freedomainradio.com/&quot;&gt;Freedomain Radio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Education... now seems to me perhaps the most authoritarian and dangerous of all the social inventions of mankind. It is the deepest foundation of the modern slave state, in which most people feel themselves to be nothing but producers, consumers, spectators, and &#39;fans,&#39; driven more and more, in all parts of their lives, by greed, envy, and fear. My concern is not to improve &#39;education&#39; but to do away with it, to end the ugly and antihuman business of people-shaping and to allow and help people to shape themselves.&quot; &lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;John Holt 1976&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/unschooling1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/unschooling1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-01-22T22:00:00.031+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Unjobbing Part 2: Experiences</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lunpBenvoP4/TkDsHgBqdnI/AAAAAAAAARs/expnGSu1f2I/s1600/deifreiheit.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-lunpBenvoP4/TkDsHgBqdnI/AAAAAAAAARs/expnGSu1f2I/s200/deifreiheit.jpg&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is a discussion of personal experiences of different stages of unjobbing: barriers to doing it, planning for it, working towards it and achieving an unjobbed life. In the discussion we refer to the book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/-Jobbing-Adult-Liberation-Handbook-Second/dp/096548341X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Un-Jobbing&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Michael Fogler. Other references in the discussion include the book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Vagabonding-Uncommon-Guide-Long-Term-Travel/dp/0812992180?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vagabonding&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&amp;nbsp;by Rolf Potts and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UF8uR6Z6KLc&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs&#39; 2005 Stanford commencement speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/unjobbing2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/unjobbing2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2011-01-22T21:00:00.025+00:00</pubDate>
<title>Unjobbing Part 1: Introduction</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CzQtSESFmRc/TkAxwUhiuxI/AAAAAAAAARo/8P7EMr5Lv7Q/s1600/790835.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-CzQtSESFmRc/TkAxwUhiuxI/AAAAAAAAARo/8P7EMr5Lv7Q/s200/790835.jpg&quot; width=&quot;127&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;The first of a two part series about &quot;Unjobbing&quot;: breaking free of the rat-race to do only things that you love with your life. In this episode we explore the idea of Unjobbing set out in the book &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/-Jobbing-Adult-Liberation-Handbook-Second/dp/096548341X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Un-Jobbing : The Adult Liberation Handbook&quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Michael Fogler. Other books referred to in the discussion include &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Rich-Dad-Poor-Money-That-Miniature/dp/0762434279?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&amp;nbsp;by Robert Kiyosaki.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/unjobbing1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/unjobbing1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2010-10-23T21:00:00.005+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Atlas Shrugged by Ayn Rand</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5N3jqg8pEIM/TjV6cYhthrI/AAAAAAAAARg/oFSI1lJXjnQ/s1600/atlasshrugged.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-5N3jqg8pEIM/TjV6cYhthrI/AAAAAAAAARg/oFSI1lJXjnQ/s200/atlasshrugged.jpg&quot; width=&quot;116&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;A discussion of Ayn Rand&#39;s classic libertarian novel&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Atlas-Shrugged-Ayn-Rand/dp/0452011876?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Atlas Shrugged&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=thevo08-20&amp;amp;l=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0452011876&quot; style=&quot;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important; padding: 0px !important;&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/atlas_shrugged.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/atlas_shrugged.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2010-07-24T22:17:00.024+01:00</pubDate>
<title>No Treason by Lysander Spooner</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;This episode is a short discussion and recommendation of Lysander Spooner&#39;s great book &quot;No Treason: The Constitution of No Authority&quot;. The book is a brilliant critique of the legality of any constitution and &amp;nbsp;the validity of any idea of a social contract.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/no_treason.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/no_treason.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2010-07-03T23:00:00.000+01:00</pubDate>
<title>The Fountainhead by Ayn Rand Part 2</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-UlasZa_swN4/TfJOLeVeW9I/AAAAAAAAAQo/eSnz2Zkoyss/s1600/fountainhead1.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-UlasZa_swN4/TfJOLeVeW9I/AAAAAAAAAQo/eSnz2Zkoyss/s200/fountainhead1.jpg&quot; width=&quot;116&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part 2 of a discussion about Ayn Rand&#39;s great individualist novel, &quot;The Fountainhead&quot; with special guest Stefan Molyneux, host of &lt;a href=&quot;http://Freedomainradio.com/&quot;&gt;Freedomainradio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/the_fountainhead_2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/the_fountainhead_2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2010-07-03T21:00:00.022+01:00</pubDate>
<title>The Fountainhead by Ayn Rand Part 1</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rPoWef9-qk8/TfCvka7h-RI/AAAAAAAAAQk/B2qIxugPQsw/s1600/fountainhead2.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-rPoWef9-qk8/TfCvka7h-RI/AAAAAAAAAQk/B2qIxugPQsw/s200/fountainhead2.jpg&quot; width=&quot;130&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;A discussion about Ayn Rand&#39;s great individualist novel, &quot;The Fountainhead&quot; with special guest Stefan Molyneux, host of &lt;a href=&quot;http://Freedomainradio.com/&quot;&gt;Freedomainradio.com&lt;/a&gt;. This is part one of a two part series.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/the_fountainhead_1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://www.thevoluntarylife.com/the_fountainhead_1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2010-05-22T21:00:00.040+01:00</pubDate>
<title>Investing for Financial Freedom: Two Approaches</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-0RH553f3MS4/TfeNGnMRx3I/AAAAAAAAAQs/Nwj6UnQ1hrE/s1600/gold.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;159&quot; src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-0RH553f3MS4/TfeNGnMRx3I/AAAAAAAAAQs/Nwj6UnQ1hrE/s200/gold.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;This episode is a discussion about two different approaches to investment. The first approach comes from Harry Browne&#39;s idea of the Permanent Portfolio, which you can find in his book&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Fail-Safe-Investing-Lifelong-Financial-Security/dp/031226321X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=thevo08-20&amp;amp;link_code=btl&amp;amp;camp=213689&amp;amp;creative=392969&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fail-Safe Investing&lt;/a&gt;. The second approach is focussed on investing purely in precious metals as a way to protect your wealth. Both approaches are concerned with investing for financial freedom and protecting your hard earned savings in the context of turbulent economic conditions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/investment.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/investment.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2010-05-10T22:30:00.017+01:00</pubDate>
<title>How I Found Freedom In An Unfree World by Harry Browne Part 2</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xA2ueW-lvDQ/TdVKzqAr14I/AAAAAAAAAQc/ZRN5VdjkQcE/s1600/HowIFoundFreedom.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xA2ueW-lvDQ/TdVKzqAr14I/AAAAAAAAAQc/ZRN5VdjkQcE/s200/HowIFoundFreedom.jpg&quot; width=&quot;128&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part two of a discussion about the ideas of personal freedom in Harry Browne&#39;s book &quot;How I Found Freedom In An Unfree World&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/how_i_found_freedom_in_an_unfree_world_2.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/how_i_found_freedom_in_an_unfree_world_2.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

<item>
<pubDate>2010-05-01T21:00:00.032+01:00</pubDate>
<title>How I Found Freedom in an Unfree World by Harry Browne Part 1</title>
<description></description>
<itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
<itunes:subtitle>&lt;div dir=&quot;ltr&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot; trbidi=&quot;on&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot; style=&quot;clear: both; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YDsV4XwmXSU/TdVMbYIRI6I/AAAAAAAAAQg/VcVakMCv5oE/s1600/howIfoundfreedomold.jpg&quot; imageanchor=&quot;1&quot; style=&quot;clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;&lt;img border=&quot;0&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-YDsV4XwmXSU/TdVMbYIRI6I/AAAAAAAAAQg/VcVakMCv5oE/s200/howIfoundfreedomold.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;Part one of a discussion about the ideas of personal freedom in Harry Browne&#39;s book &quot;How I Found Freedom In An Unfree World&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thevoluntarylife.com/how_i_found_freedom_in_an_unfree_world_1.mp3&quot;&gt;Podcast Episode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</itunes:subtitle>
<enclosure type='audio/mpeg' url='http://thevoluntarylife.com/how_i_found_freedom_in_an_unfree_world_1.mp3' length='0'/>
<itunes:author>Jake Desyllas</itunes:author>
<itunes:summary></itunes:summary>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
